# C. JAMAR MUHAMMAD

P.O. Box 524 • 5306 Redlick Road • Lorman, MS 39096 • (601) 431-2499 • jamar@theatricalharmony.com

## **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

I am a dedicated communications and media specialist, marketing and public relations agent, graphic designer, social media consultant/manager, editor, and writer that pays close attention to detail. My skills include leadership, management and content creation, and I have a stellar record of client satisfaction. I'm a dynamic, highly organized, adaptable and efficient copy editor and proofreader with a keen eye for accuracy. I develop strategies to communicate brand messaging clearly to the intended audience. I am experienced in helping my clients to meet their goals, whether it's developing a digital profile, managing an email list and newsletter, website, video hosting platform or blog.

I am ready to work with a company that will allow me to utilize my skills in a work environment that will offer challenge and growth, and where I can make a meaningful impact.

### SKILLS & AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Thorough knowledge of effective media, public relations and communications.
- Advanced knowledge of all aspects of external communications, including but not limited to traditional and social (Facebook, Twitter) media, direct mail, online communications, conferences, press and events.
- Demonstrated understanding of the news media, its structures and technology for reporting news.
- Excellent written communications skills, including capacity to communicate complex ideas compellingly to a variety of audiences.
- Effectively using principles of written communication, graphical layout and multimedia techniques appropriate to web-based communication, ensuring that work products are clear, usable and effectively convey the intended messages and information.
- Understanding trends in marketing, identity building, and communication strategies for governmental organizations.
- Expertise in conducting research, locating information related to the request and critically evaluating the research findings.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Aisha Sanders for Mississippi State House campaign (District 96), Natchez, MS August 2019 - November 2019 Communications and Digital Director

- Developed and delivered the candidate's message through social media. This included monitoring and posting to the candidate's Facebook page, Twitter account and Instagram page, as well as drafting blogs for various sites, and working with a team to support these initiatives.
- Created and developed candidate's website, supplying a rich user experience for voters.
- Wrote and/or coordinated copywriting efforts for email blasts, website copy, display ads, fixing and cleaning up bios, etc.
- Cultivated relationships on behalf of the candidate with members of the press—including journalists, bloggers and
  other media outlets—understanding the interests of each contact.
- Wrote and edited communications plans, news releases and op/eds to advance candidate's campaign.
- Developed and maintained a coordinated network of information-sharing among internal staff to integrate communications efforts across the campaign.
- Collaborated with the candidate's team to recommend and implement a proactive communications program.
- Communicated with the media as the key spokesperson.
- Established rapport with the public, developing and maintaining a network of contacts who could provide information, help, and access to the candidate.
- Set up interviews, and identified media opportunities for the campaign.
- Wrote all campaign literature, drafted speeches for candidate, and created copy for campaign website.
- Wrote copy for internal and external communications (newsletters, emails, social media, etc).
- Led campaign's writing, graphic design, video, and social media activities.
- Advised the candidate and senior staff on all proactive, reactive and crisis communications.
- Managed production of communications materials across a broad range of digital, video and print products.
- Conveyed complex issues, events and concepts in succinct, easy-to-understand language, both in writing and orally.
- Advised and coordinated with staff on strategic communications issues, including ways the candidate could be

- positively positioned and portrayed in the news media, social media, the community, other government agencies and community partners.
- Created and designed campaign mailer, and managed direct mail strategy and implementation across District 96.

Carmen Brooks-Drake for Adams County Prosecutor camp

# Carmen Brooks-Drake for Adams County Prosecutor campaign, Natchez, MS Digital Director & Graphic Designer for successful run-off period of campaign

- Led campaign's writing, graphic design, video, and social media activities during run-off period of campaign.
- Developed and delivered the candidate's message through social media. This included monitoring and posting to the campaign's Facebook page.
- Designed all campaign media, which included logo update for run-off, and creation of all graphics for social media.
- Created and designed campaign mailer, and managed direct mail strategy and implementation across Adams County.

# Mississipi State Senator Albert Butler's re-election campaign, Port Gibson, MS Communications and Digital Director for successful re-election campaign March 2019 - August 2019

- Collaborated with the candidate's team to recommend and implement a proactive communications program.
- Built relationships with the press, and communicated with the media as the key spokesperson.
- Developed and delivered the candidate's message through social media. This included monitoring and posting to the candidate's Facebook page.
- Created and developed candidate's website, supplying a rich user experience for voters.
- Established rapport with the public, developing and maintaining a network of contacts who could provide information, help, and access to the candidate.
- Set up interviews, and identified media opportunities for the campaign.
- Communicated with the media as the key spokesperson.
- Wrote all campaign literature, drafted speeches for candidate, and created copy for campaign website.
- Wrote copy for internal and external communications (newsletters, emails, social media, etc).
- Advised the candidate and senior staff on all proactive, reactive and crisis communications.
- Managed production of communications materials across a broad range of digital, video and print products.
- Conveyed complex issues, events and concepts in succinct, easy-to-understand language, both in writing and orally.
- Advised and coordinated with staff on strategic communications issues, including ways the candidate could be
  positively positioned and portrayed in the news media, social media, the community, other government agencies and
  community partners.
- Developed and maintained a coordinated network of information-sharing among internal staff to integrate communications efforts across the campaign.

# Shameca Collins for District Attorney (District 6) campaign, Natchez, MS Communications and Digital Director for successful district-wide campaign

- Built relationships with the press, and communicated with the media as the key spokesperson.
- Set up interviews, and identified media opportunities for the campaign.
- Communicated with the media as the key spokesperson.
- Wrote all campaign literature, drafted speeches for candidate, and created copy for campaign website.
- Wrote copy for internal and external communications (newsletters, emails, social media, etc).
- Developed and delivered the candidate's message through social media. This included monitoring and posting to the candidate's Facebook page.
- Advised the candidate and senior staff on all proactive, reactive and crisis communications.
- Managed production of communications materials across a broad range of digital, video and print products.

# Jeffery Harness for Mississippi State House District 85 campaign, Fayette, MS September 2018 - November 2018 Campaign Manager during special election to fill House Seat vacancy

- Developed and delivered the candidate's message through social media. This included monitoring and posting to the candidate's Facebook page.
- Oversaw all aspects of the research, drafting and implementation of campaign plan.
- Defined roles and negotiated contracts with all vendors, consultants, and staff including general, fundraising, field,

and media.

- Hired and managed campaign staff.
- Led fundraising team in identifying and soliciting funds for significant fundraising efforts.
- Built broad, effective grassroots campaign including, but not limited to, coalition building.
- Oversaw the development of all paid media production, distribution and broadcast (TV, radio, and direct mail).
- Developed and maintained a coordinated network of information-sharing among internal staff to integrate communications efforts across the campaign.

### Londell "Rock" Eanochs for Mayor campaign, Fayette, MS

December 2016 - June 2017

#### Communications Director for successful mayoral campaign

- Built relationships with the press, and communicated with the media as the key spokesperson.
- Set up interviews, and identified media opportunities for the campaign.
- Wrote all campaign literature, drafted speeches for candidate, and created copy for campaign website.
- Wrote copy for internal and external communications (newsletters, emails, social media, etc).
- Advised the mayoral candidate and senior staff on all proactive, reactive and crisis communications.
- Managed production of communications materials across a broad range of digital, video and print products.
- Wrote and edited communications plans, news releases and op/eds to advance candidate's campaign.

#### Theatrical Harmony Media, Detroit, MI

January 2016 - Present

#### CEO, Freelance Media Specialist, Content Writer, Public Relations, Media Strategist

- Write content for articles, web content and press releases.
- Develop advertising materials and copy in coordination with art department.
- Monitor and edit copy in accordance with guidelines and requirements.
- Develop proofing and marketing stylebooks and templates and maintain company style.
- Contact various guests to appear on both television and radio programs. These include high-profile guests such as famed Senator Alan Simpson, renowned astrophysicist Dr. Neil deGrasse Tyson, Attorney Gloria Allred and many more.
- Research, pitch and develop show concepts and stories.
- Maintain a strong rolodex, solid knowledge of current events, pop culture, social media and current entertainment industry trends.
- Media outreach and planning, marketing and special communication services.
- Build social media campaigns, and assist with video productions.

#### SOS Communications, Detroit, MI

April 2013 - June 2016

#### Copy Editor

- Wrote content for articles, web content and press releases.
- Developed advertising materials and copy in coordination with art department.
- Monitored and edited copy in accordance with guidelines and requirements.
- Developed proofing and marketing stylebooks and templates and maintained company style.

#### No Water, No Life, NYC, New York

December 2012 - January 2015

#### Transcriber

- Provided transcription services for No Water, No Life on an as-needed basis.
- Familiarized myself with terminology related to wildlife preservation and water conservancy to aid with transcription tasks.
- Transcribed videos and audio of interviews conducted with experts across the country.

## Daily Transcription, Los Angeles, CA

**October 2011 - April 2012** 

#### Transcriber

- Served as an overflow transcriber for Daily Transcription
- Utilized 85 wpm/0 mistakes skill to provide quick and diligent transcription for LA based company.

- Transcribed audio from movies, reality shows, comedy shows, meetings and phone conversations.
- Provided 24 hour turnaround for 95% of transcriptions.

## Fayette Board of Tourism, Fayette, MS

#### September 2011 - March 2013

#### Council Member

- Clearly articulated the organization's mission to the public and garnered support from the community.
- Gathered important feedback information polled to the community regarding what interests them within the city.
- Assisted in developing the annual budget and ensuring that proper financial controls are in place.
- Secured adequate resources for the organization to fulfill its mission.
- Upon completion of a successful project plan, determined which programs were consistent with the organization's mission and monitored their effectiveness.

### Shabazz Printing, Fayette, MS

#### July 2006 - Present

### Editor/Graphic Designer/Copywriter

- Graphic designer for various marketing packages ranging from business cards to logo and book design.
- Planning and provisioning of marketing techniques to promote awareness of company.
- Assistant editor for monthly magazine.
- Schedule customer appointments and corporate meetings.
- Maintain unwavering communications with company departments to ensure utmost customer satisfaction.
- Comply with strict handle times for customer projects and department meetings.

#### **EDUCATION**

Muhammad's University, Lorman, MS B.A. in Communication 2002-2006

## REFERENCES

**District Attorney Shameca Collins** 601-870-7811

**Dr. Ieesha Ramsey** 937-831-1215

Kim Brown Robinson 601-519-1131